Hi, everyone my name is to...g of a product lead for the marketing
platforms team the team that is responsible for building and operating microsoft's affiliate
program I'm here to give you an overview about our affiliate program
and most importantly share with you are plans for its expansion into
absent games music video and movies this expansion will allow
developers and partners an exciting new way to monetize
their relationship with microsoft developers and partners can
...commission on referrals that they send to us.
If...developer or a partner or retailer who has
been driving traffic to us via your marketing campaigns or perhaps want
to this is your chance to monetize the sales that occur
...those channels.
This program opens infinite new possibilities to
make more money promoting microsoft products.
So, without further ado let me tell you how you can make
more money promoting microsoft products.
Today I will start this presentation with the basics of
...affiliate program and talk to-you about the who what why and how all
of the affiliate program along with microsoft's own
commission structures and then followed by some technical details
around what tools and resources we will have available to the affiliates
plus I will share with you some details around what makes microsoft's
affiliate program unique compared to its...finally I will
complete conclude with information on how to get started today?
So, let's start with a high-level overview of in...program and the purpose that it serves a
philly programs first and foremost are a
huge monetize a shun opportunity for developers partners and retailers
you can earn a commission by simply linking to thousands of apps
gains songs as well as movies and tv shows.
You as an affiliate
utilized specialized links across your website or from inside
your app to earn money on each referral plus as part of being.
Part of the affiliate program you
get insights into what selling allowing you to optimize your marketing efforts
and in return grow your revenue via the affiliate program.
Additionally another strong benefit of joining the affiliate program is that you
get access to powerful tools and rich data about microsoft's product
catalog which is only available to affiliate partners.
who can use in...program well just about anyone with the website
...app if you are content creators such as a developer a publishing
house a music label you can use in a...program in many different ways to
promote the content you create and drive traffic to the windows store or
...web store, for example, if you...app developer you can cross promote the
apps the you create...in app banners to gain not only installs but also
...commission on those you can also use and app
drive traffic to other relevant product categories such as music or video?
And, perhaps you might want also drive referrals to
our physical products such as surface xbox and...
For music labels...also certain scenarios you can perhaps leverage the
fairly program for you can use the affiliate program to drive referrals in
...store to not only earn money from
the downloads but also earn commissions by simply referring them to
our store think about all the possibilities that are available
to whether you use your website or you use social media or
you use your email marketing campaigns to drive traffic to us.
If your content
curators such as a retailer and oem a blog article
...new site who wants to q rate a story around
apps and gains movies...video you can also
...a commission by sending those referrals to us you will not only help your
audience discover great new entertainment but also get rewarded for those
efforts so let me give you some specific examples.
If you're a blogger promoting favorite tv shows movies you
can monetize that blog by sending those referrals to us.
Apps that are showcasing new on sale
are top content can monetize their apps by
sending the qualified referrals into the windows store or our web store.
Oem and
retailers can tell a windows ecosystem story on their website
in social media or in email and send traffic to us
while also earn income a commission on those downloads the possibilities of how
it affiliate program can be used to monetize our
endless so we want you to get creative in driving those referrals to us.
Now that you're imagine perhaps infinite ways in which you
can drive traffic to the windows store or our web store let me give you
a high-level overview of how the affiliate program works and
who's involved in tracking the conversions there are three important
parties that play a key role the affiliate publisher which is you
the developer the blog...the retailer the oem.
Then there is the affiliate network who you sign up
...sign up with and who provides you the platform
the reports and commission...and of course there's a store which you
drive traffic to and when a conversion occurs on the store?
That sale is reported to the affiliate network who pays you out the
commission so let me just quickly go over how this process works you.
The affiliate publisher ads...links to your site or your
app and drive traffic via those links to the windows store.
Clicks on the links are recorded in the affiliate network.
When a customer converts?
The sale is reported to the affiliate network and
walla the affiliate
network then provides you detailed reports as well as
pays you out your commission now they you
know-how the affiliate program works let me give you
an idea about the wide variety of products that you can promote via microsoft's
...program simply put all products that are sold via
are web store or our
windows store are eligible for an affiliate commission.
Currently you are able to promote surface office
three sixty-five xbox microsoft
band and a lot of other physical and downloadable software.
You can earn a commission from up to from starting from two percent all the way up
to ten percent with the very generous thirty...attribution
window to account for the longer consideration period that
customers have for physical products this program has been live since two thousand
eight and has paid out millions of dollars in commissions to affiliates?
Building on the success.
Of this affiliate program.
For the...ten launch and happy to announce that we will
be adding support for a lot of new products.
Such as absent
games which will include in app purchases music's
which will include download and streaming subscription.
And, videos including popular tv shows and movies such as
blockbusters and new releases.
...absent games as well as
music and video you will earn a seven percent commission.
Additionally for a single download such as a single song or
in ninety nine cents app the purchased consideration process that
...customer goes through is fairly short so we will give you
a commission for any paid download within a twenty four hour
period plus in order to allow you to make a lot of money promoting microsoft
apps we carefully examine the data surrounding the average life of an app
and also examined the pattern of in app purchases which happen mostly over a weekend.
And, therefore we will provide you a very attractive
...industry leading attribution window of fourteen days for
an app purchases this is fourteen
times longer than what our competitors offer.
This attractive window will provide a highly lucrative
opportunity to monetize your free medium apps and games developers I hope
you're excited about take an are taking note of this huge monetize a shun opportunity.
For subscriptions such as music streaming we
also provide an attractive attribution window of six months.
During the six-month period we will pay
you a commission on each monthly renewal.
This six not commission window again is six times longer than what
our competitors offer created a very lucrative opportunity to make a
lot of money referring qualified subscribers to us.
So, I hope you're hearing the sound of could ching from these attractive terms because we
design these terms with you and mind because we want you to make a
lot of money promoting microsoft products I hope you're excited to
jump friday so let's shift gears a little bit and talk about the links and the
link building tools that are available for this program to work.
Use and affiliate utilize...links
across your website in your app to track referrals.
Links utilize include a
programme id which corresponds to microsoft's affiliate program
and affiliate id which corresponds to you and the
...url for the product that you want to promote.
One-c user clicks on the link the url shown above
...to the url shown below on the slide which
combines all the tracking parameters into a single affiliate tracking code.
These urls are critical to tracking the philly commission and therefore a high
degree of vigilance is required to ensure that your creating links that will work.
So, in order to help you
create this lengths we will be providing you a few different tools.
The first is the
catalog feeds which are full flat file of the app syncs
...music and video as well as surface
pc's xbox and more.
For any given country these feeds will contain
rich metadata about the product itself such as the image the
...the and the deep link url this type of catalog feed is
suited to create thousands of affiliate links on-the-fly.
...is best suited for somebody who's a tech savvy partner who
can consume very large-size data files to create affiliate links we
will also offer and easy low-tech option to develop links like
the link builder for an affiliate partners that are interested in developing a
few links rather than generating thousands of affiliate links?
Plus for app developers we will provide badge art that can be
used in combination with affiliate links so that you can earn a commission on
download when a customer clicks on the windows store badge
download your app these linking tools will provide options for all types of a
philly partners to reliably build links and generate revenue.
Additionally once your links are placed across your website and your apps.
You will be able to see detailed
skew level reports on what is selling.
This will empower you to use the data to optimize your marketing
efforts.
This data gives you the our to utilize it to
make revenue driving decisions and continue to enhance your marketing efforts.
...covered a lot during the short time
but there's one important thing that I want you to take away.
If you want to make money promoting microsoft
products you should be using the affiliate program.
There are a few things that I want to emphasize from this presentation and I want you to take
away with you we provide very long
attribution windows for an app purchases at fourteen days which again
is fourteen times longer than our competition.
...the only affiliate program to offer this longer
...attribution window for...app purchases.
Plus if it customers logged in we can track them across devices
and across stores that is the web store and the store on windows
This cross device and cross store attribution also
creates unique opportunities to aren't a lot more revenue.
And, then on the reporting front we pool provide you a quick turn-around for
...reporting to allow you to make smarter decisions about your marketing
efforts.
Last but perhaps most importantly
we are the only affiliate program that allows you to
earn a commission promoting windows apps for retailers
and oem who want to tell it windows ecosystem story
this is your chance to make money for your efforts
for app developers who are already using social media and other
marketing efforts to promote your apps this is your chance to
...commission for your marketing efforts.
So, with that I hope you will become...affiliate partner and avail
of the opportunity to make lots of money for by referring customers
to us you can get started today at http.
Colin back flashback slash aka dot microsoft
back slash microsoft affiliates and...up today via
are worldwide partner...integral we will send notifications
when absent games music and
video are available to promote so be sure to register here.
In the meantime you can promote our current product categories
of surface xbox office...and more.
So, by now I hope you're excited and with that I hope you will become
...philly partner and avail the opportunity to make lots of money
by referring customers to us you can get started today at http.
Colin backs flashbacks slash aka dot microsoft
back slash microsoft affiliates and sign up
...are worldwide partner tray wr integral we
will send notification about absent games music and video when
they're available to promote so we want you to register here in the meantime
you can promote our current product categories of surface xbox office
pc's and more.
We look forward to seeing all the creative ways in which
you utilize the affiliate program to send referrals to us thank you.